Emil L. Larsen papers, 1931-1962
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Papers relating to Emil L. Larsen, 1931-1962
AZ 440
Includes correspondence with university and college athletic directors, coaches, and faculty representatives, as well as officers and members of various other athletic conferences, of the National Association of Football Commissioners, and of the National Collegiate Athletic Assocation.
Larson, Emil L., 1888-1968
6.5 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
Professor of Education, University of Arizona.
Organization
This collection is organized into eleven series:
I. Border Intercollegiate Althetic Conference, 1930-1962
II. Various Athletic Conferences, 1941-1962
III. National Association of Football Commissioners/National Association of Collegiate Commissioners, 1945-1965
IV. National Collegiate Athletic Association, 1936-1969
V. Athletic Directors, Coaches, Managers, 1938-1964
VI. University and College Coaches' Ratings of Officials, 1950-1961
VII. Border Conference Officials Association, 1940-1963
VIII. Various Officials' Association, 1940-1954
IX. Bown Games, 1944-58
X. Football Materials, 1944-1971
XI. Basketball Materials, 1949-1971
Scope and Content Note
Includes correspondence with university and college athletic directors, coaches, and faculty representatives, as well as officers and members of various other athletic conferences, of the National Association of Football Commissioners, and of the National Collegiate Athletic Assocation. Also minutes of meetings, financial records, ratings, examinations, rules handbooks, publications, photographs, and files (1965-1971) on the Arizona Football and Basketball Halls of Fame.
Access Terms
Larson, Emil L.
University of Arizona -- Sports -- History
National Collegiate Athletic Association
Border Intercollegiate Athletic Conference
National Association of Football Commissioners
University of Arizona -- Faculty
University of Arizona -- Sports
College sports -- Arizona -- History
Athletics -- Arizona -- History
Football -- Arizona -- History
Basketball -- Arizona -- History
Correspondence
Container List
- Series I: Border Intercollegiate Althetic Conference, 1931-1962
  - General Materials
    - History (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes of Meetings, v. 1 (1931-May 1942), v.2 (November 1942-1961), Index. 1931-1961 (Box 1)
    - Plaque "presented to Dr. Emil L. Larson in recognition of distinguished leadership and exceptional service as Commissioner from 1931-1962." 1962 (Box 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1940, 1943-1962 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Financial Records, 1939-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bulletins on Rules, 1931-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Statistics and Records, 1931-1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - All-Conference Teams (Football), 1949, 1952-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - All-Conference Teams (Basketball), 1949, 1952-1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Representatives
    - General Memorandum, etc. No date (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Arizona State Teachers College/Arizona State College, Flagstaff (Osborn, Francis C.) 1943-1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Arizona State Teachers College/Arizona State College, Tempe (Southern, C.B.) 1944-1953 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Arizona State Teachers College/Arizona State College, Tempe (Thomas, Alfred, Jr.) 1953-1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Hardin-Simmons University (Campbell, L.Q., 1943-1945), (Collings, Robert A., 1946-1954), (Arrant, Hiram R., 1956-1962) 1943-1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - New Mexico College of Agriculture & Mechanic Arts (Hamiel, G.R.) 1943-1956 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Texas College of Mines & Metallurgy/Texas Western College (Knapp, B.J.) 1945-1961 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Texas Technological College (Stangel, W.L., 1943-1948), (Davis, J. William, 1948-1962) 1943-1962 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - University of Arizona (Lesher, C. Zaner) 1945-1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - University of New Mexico (Hume, William, II, 1943), (Castetter, Edward F., 1943-1945), (Hill, W.W., 1945-1946) 1943-1946 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - West Texas State Teachers College/West Texas State College (Shirley, D.A., 1943-1947), (Jones, W.Mitchell, 1956-1962) 1943-1962 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series II: Various Athletic Conferences, 1941-1967
  - Big Six Intercollegiate Athletic Conference/Missouri Valley InterCollegiate Assoc./Big Eight Conference (Peters, Reaves E., 1945-1961) 1945-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Missouri Valley Conference (Eilers, Arthur E.) 1941-1955 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Missouri Valley Conference (Neve, Norwall) 1957-1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Missouri Valley Conference (University of Wichita vs. West Texas State College) November 15, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Missouri Valley Conference (Miscellaneous Items) No date (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mountain States Conference (Warner, Homer C.) 1945-1949 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mountain States Conference (Romney, E. L.) 1949-1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mountain States Conference (Brechler, Paul) 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Pacific Coast Intercollegiate Athletic Conference (Various) No date (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pacific Coast Intercollegiate Athletic Conference (Miscellaneous Bulletins, etc.) No date (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Pacific Coast Intercollegiate Athletic Conference (Athletic Codes) No date (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Intercollegiate Conference (Big Ten) 1941-1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Central Office for Eastern Intercollegiate Athletics/Eastern, College Athletic Conference (Bushnell, Asa A., and others, 1943-1952) 1943-1952 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Eastern Intercollegiate Football Association (Bulletins, 1948-1953) 1948-1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Southeastern Conference (Moore, Bernie H.) 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Southern Conference, 1951-1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Southwest Athletic Conference (includes Abb Curtis, Howard Grubbs, James Stewart, and others) 1943-1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Western Athletic Conference (Yearbook) 1964-65 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Rules and Regulations of Intercollegiate Athletic Conferences in the United States." (Waldo M. Dicus, Emil L. Larson) No date (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Series III: National Association of Football Commissioners/National Assocaiton of Collegiate Commissioners, 1945-62
  - Constitution: 1965 Directory 1965 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Bushnell, Asa S.) 1945-1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Corespondence (Hutches, A.R.) 1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Peters, Reaves E.) 1945-1954 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Schmidt, Victor O.) 1950-1954 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Meetings No date (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Photographs No date (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Basketball Clinics: Proceedings, 1st -6th, 8th- 13th 1950-1955, 1957-1962 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series IV: National Collegiate Athletic Association, 1936-1969
  - Correspondence 1943-1962 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Emil L. Larson Tribute 1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Constitution and By-Laws 1952, 1959, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - National Collegiate Championships 1958, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, The Blue Book of College Athletics 1936-1937, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series V: Athletic Directors, Coaches, and Managers, 1944-1962
  - Arizona State Teachers College/Arizona State College, Flagstaff 1944-1952 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Brickey, Frank, Director, 1944-1947
    McCreary, A.M., Director, 1947-1948
    Insley, Jiggs, Director, 1949-1950
    Ladyko, Emil, Football Coach, 1949
    Pederson, John N., Football Coach, 1951-1952
  - Arizona State College, Tempe 1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Kinzle, Don, Executive Manager, Director 1947-1951
  - Arizona State College, Tempe 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Van Petten, D.R., Director, 1952-1954
  - Arizona State College, Tempe 1946-1952 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Lillico, Tom, Graduate Manager, 1946-1952
  - Arizona State College/Arizona State University, Tempe 1954-1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Smith, Clyde, Football Coach, Director, 1954-1961
  - Arizona State College/Arizona State University, Tempe 1952-1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Rispoli, Frank, Assistant Director, Graduate Manager, 1952-1962
  - Arizona State College/Arizona State University, Tempe 1946-1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Coutchie, Steve A., Football Coach, 1946
    Doherty, Edward, Football Coach, 1948-1950
    Kush, Frank, Football Coach, 1958-1960
    Lavik, R.H., Basketball Coach, Director, 1946-1947
    Kajikawa, Bill, Basketball Coach, 1949-1955
    Wulk, Ned, Basketball Coach, 1957-1962
    Winkles, Bob, Baseball Coach, 1958
  - Brigham Young University 1946-1953 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Kimball, Edwin R., Football Coach, Director, 1946-1953
  - Colorado College 1944-1946 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    White, Harold A., Football Coach, 1944-1946
  - Hardin-Simmons University 1946-1951 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Woodson, Warren, Director, 1946-1951
  - Hardin-Simmons University 1952-1962 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Ledbetter, E.W., Director, 1952-1962
  - Hardin-Simmons University 1946-1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Bradshaw, W.W., Basketball Coach, 1946-1947
    Evans, Murray, Football Coach, 1952
    Scott, Bill, Basketball Coach, 1953-1962
  - New Mexico College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts 1944-1946 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    Laabs, Kermit, Director, 1944-1946
  - New Mexico College of Agricultue and Mechanic Arts/New Mexico State University 1953-1964 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Askew, Presley, Director, 1953-1958; Basketball Coach, 1959-1964
  - New Mexico College of Agricultue and Mechanic Arts/New Mexico State University 1946-1962 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Hines, Jerry, Director, 1946-1948
    Moll, C.S., Director, 1950
    McCarty, George, Director, 1951-1952
    Woodson, Warren, Director, 1958-1962
  - New Mexico College of Agricultue and Mechanic Arts/New Mexico State University 1946-1962 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Curfman, Raymond, Football Coach, 1946-1947
    Corley, Vaughn, Football Coach, 1948-1949
    Gunn, John T., Basketball Coach, 1947
    Hynes, Joseph D., Business Manager, 1958-1960
    Browne, Ken, (Business Manager?), 1961-1962
  - Phoenix College 1948-1961 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Hoy, George, Director, 1948-1955
    Riggs, John D., Director, 1957-1961
    Miscellaneous corresondence with various others
  - Texas College of Mines/Texas Western College 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Curtice, Jack, Director, 1946-1949
  - Texas College of Mines/Texas Western College 1947-1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Collins, Ben, Director, 1959-1961
    Waters, Dale B., Basketball Coach, 1947
    Moore, Ross, Basketball Coach, 1947
    McCarty, George, Basketball Coach, 1953-1962
    Davis, Harold L., Basketball Coach, 1959-1960
    Haskins, Don, Basketball Coach, 1961
  - Texas Western College 1950-1958 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Brumbelow, Mike, Director, 1950-1958
  - Texas Technological College 1944-1950 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Jennings, Morley, Director, 1944-1950
  - Texas Technological College 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Weaver, DeWitt, Director, 1951-1956
  - Texas Technological College 1944-1955 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Morgan, Dell, Football Coach, 1944-1949
    Nichols, W.L. Track Coach, 1946
    Huffman, B., Basketball Coach, 1946
    Robinson, P., Basketball Coach, 1947-1955
  - University of Arizona 1946-1962 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    McKale, J.F., Director, 1947-1954
    Clausen, M.R., Director, 1958-1961
    Casteel, Mike, Football Coach, 1946
    Winslow, Robert, Football Coach, 1949
    Woodson, Warren, Football Coach, 1954
    Enke, Fred, Basketball Coach, 1951-1960
    Larson, Bruce, Basketball Coach, 1960-1962
  - University of Arizona 1942-1962 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Graduate Managers, 1942-1962
  - University of Arizona 1938, 1944, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    "Batiste Material." Relating to track records of Joe and Fred Batiste, Tucson High School, 1938 and 1944, and Fred's 1950 participation in UA Football.
  - University of Arkansas 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Lambert, Eugene, Basketball Coach, 1946-1949
  - University of New Mexico 1944-1949 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    White, George, Director, 1944-1949
  - University of New Mexico 1943-1953 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Barnes, W., Football Coach, 1943-1946
    Clements, W., Basketball Coach, 1946-1953
    Huffman, B., Football Coach, Director, 1947-1951
    Various Managers
  - University of Texas 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Bible, Dana X., Director, 1945-1946
  - West Texas State College 1948-1962 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Kimbrough, Frank, Football Coach, Director, 1948-1962
  - West Texas State College 1944-1958 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Miller, W.A., Football Coach, Director, 1944-1958
  - West Texas State College 1946-1961 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Baggett, Al, Director, 1946
    Nicklaus, W.W., Football Coach, 1946-1947
    Price, Bordon, Basketball Coach, 1957-1958
    LaFollette, Metz, Basketball Coach, 1959-1961
  - Correspondence with various other Directors and Coaches 1944-1962 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Ratings of Officicals, 1950-1962
  - Football 1950-1961 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Arizona State College, Flagstaff, 1950
    Arizona State College, Arizona State University, Tempe, 1950-1961
    Hardin-Simmons University, 1950-1961
    New Mexico College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts/New Mexico State University, 1950-1961
  - Football 1950-1961 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Texas Technological College, 1953
    Texas Western College, 1950-1961
    University of Arizona, 1950-1961
    University of New Mexico, 1950-1953
    West Texas State College, 1950-1961
  - Basketball 1958-1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Arizona State College, Flagstaff, 1958-1961
    Arizona State University, Tempe, 1958-1962
    Hardin-Simmons University, 1959-1962
  - Basketball 1958-1962 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    New Mexico College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts/New Mexico State University, 1958-1961
    Phoenix College, 1958-1961
    Texas Western College, 1958-1962
  - Basketball 1958-1962 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    University of Arizona, 1958-1962
    University of New Mexico, 1958-1961
    West Texas State College, 1959-1962
- Series VII: Border Conference Officials Association, 1940-1962
  - General Materials
    - Membership Lists (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1940-1961 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Forms and Emblems (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Meetings (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Photographs (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ratings (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Assignments; Football (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Assignments; Basketball (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Football Examinations and Scores (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Members
    - Arthur, Percy 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Ballard, Virgil 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Barrett, Curtis 1949-1953 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Benson, G. M. 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Berry, Charles M. 1942-1949 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Biellli, S.J. 1945-1950 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bliss, Harry 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Boney, R.E. 1942-1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bost, Wallace 1946 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bradshaw, R.J. 1947-1950 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Brown, C.M. 1945-1956 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Cain, Stina 1942-1956 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Caldwell, W.R. 1942-1945 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Carter, Jerry 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Cearlley, Jess 1943-1956 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Clements, W.W. 1949 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Coffman, Ted 1950 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Coleman, A.M. 1945-1947 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Combs, John T. 1957 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Corley, Vaughn 1956 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Connelley, Warren 1942-1956 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Cornelius, B.O. 1945-1953 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Coutchie, S.A. 1942-1950 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Crosby, John 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Davidson, Guy 1941-1950 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Davis, Barto 1944-1953 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Deal, Ralph 1946-1956 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Dillion, Otto 1942-1949 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Doolen, B.C. 1941-1950 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Dowell, Robert 1945-1949 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Duval, C.A. 1944-1949 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Ellis, John W. 1946-1950 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - England, Byron 1946-1950 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Finley, Charles 1945-1946 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Folsom, Haskell 1945-1950 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Gann, Cotton 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Glenn, Tom 1950 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Greer, H.K. 1940-1946 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Gregor, Judd 1947-1956 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Hamilton, A.C. 1945-1950 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Hanhila, Matt O. 1949-1955 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Harris, C.H. 1946-1951 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Harris, W.C.O. 1945-1950 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Hart, John L. 1946-1956 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Harvey, Philip W. 1945-1948 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Hays, Guyton 1946-1950 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Hays, Guyton 1949-1963 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Hernandez, F. Louis 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Hinds, Bruce 1942-1950 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Holmes, Eugene 1949-1957 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Holmes, Joe B. 1947-1950 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Hooks, H. Brian 1945 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Hoy, George D. 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Isbell, Jeff 1945-1949 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Jackson, Gib 1945-1953 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Jarnagin, W.C. 1949-1950 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Jones, Verne D. 1945-1956 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Kisner, W.H. 1949-1953 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Laabs, Kermit 1942-1956 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Lawson, William D. 1946-1961 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Ledbetter, C.H. 1944-1950 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Leissner, F.F. 1946-1947 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Lennox, Harry 1947-1950 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Lindgren, A.F. 1946 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Lunceford, R.C. 1945 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - McKinney, Burns 1946-1956 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - McNutt, Jack S. 1942-1956 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Maedgen, James R. 1945-1950 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Milner, W.J. 1946-1950 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Miranda, Dan 1948-1953 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Morse, Milton 1945-1949 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Mulcahy, H.I. "Iggy" 1945-1950 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Mulvey, Arthur C. 1945-1950 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Malone, James 1962 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Miller, Eddie 1947 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Miller, Joseph 1953-1957 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Morris, A.B. 1946 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Murphy, Pat 1942-1946 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Phillips, Harry 1946-1956 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Pacells, R.P. 1945-1947 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Porter, Asa 1941 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Pressley, J.E. 1953-1960 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Riggs, Johnnie 1945-1954 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Romney, Elwood 1944-1946 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Sacks, Benny 1945 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Secrist, Delbert 1940-1950 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Sellers, Goodson 1946-1948 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Shelton, Harl 1945-1948 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Smith, C. E. 1946-1956 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Stalls, Tony 1942-1945 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Stambach, Harold 1950 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Steverson, Norris 1949-1955 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Stofft, Fred 1947-1950 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Swearengen, Earl 1947-1953 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Sweeney, Charles B. 1944-1950 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Taylor, Harry 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Taylor, Jack J. 1946-1957 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Taylor, Willard 1949-1955 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Teal, William 1945-1956 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Thayer, J. W. "Duke" 1946-1957 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Trigg, Charlie 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Vaughn, Finis 1948-1950 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Wafer, Clyde 1945-1950 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Walker, J. Prentice 1945-1950 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Wall, C. I. 1945-1946 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Ward, Morris W. 1949-1962 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - West, J.W. 1946-1954 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Wilkins, E.H. 1948-1950 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Willard, M.C. 1950 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Williamson, Mike 1945-1953 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Wilson, Glenn 1948 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Wood, B.P. 1945-1949 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Applications Not Filled, A-Z (Box 14, Folder 21-23)
- Series VIII: Various Officials' Associations, 1940-1963
  - Eastern Association of Intercollegiate Football Officials 1946, 1953, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Membership and Ranking lists, 1946, 1953; Annual Clinic and Business Meeting, September 9, 1950.
  - Intercollegiate Football Officials Association of California 1948-1950 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Correspondence with Hal Saunders, Secretary, 1948-1950
  - International Association of Approved Basketball Officials 1957-1963 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Handbook, 1957-1958; 1962-1963
  - National Association of Approved Basketball Officials 1940-1949 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Handbook, 1944-1945; Examinations, 1940-1941, 1948-1949; Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1944-1946.
  - Southeastern Conference Football Officials Association 1947-1954 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Correspondence with George Gardner, Secretary Treasurer, 1947-1954.
  - Southern Conference Booking Office 1946-1951 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Ranking Lists, 1947, 1949, 1950; Official Bulletins, various issues, 1947-1951; Correspondence with A.R. Hutchens, Secretary, 1946-1951, including N.C.A.A. Football Rules Committee correspondence.
  - Southern Football Officials Association 1944-1946 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Regulations, 1944; Ranking lists, 1945; Official Bulletin, various issues, 1944-1946; misc. items.
  - Southwest Football Officials' Association 1948 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Officers and Membership List, 1948; miscellaneous items.
  - Miscellaneous Officials Groups (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Series IX: Bowl Games, 1944-1958
  - Sun Bowl 1944-1958 (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
  - Salad Bowl 1951-1955 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
  - Miscellaneous Bowl Games (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Series X: Football Materials, 1944-1971
  - Football Officiating (Miscellaneous Materials) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Football Officicals Manuals (Various) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Football Rules, A.R. Hutchens: "A Recodification of N.C.A.A. Football Rules" 1947 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Football Rules, N.C.A.A. 1947, 1961, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Football Rules, Krieger, E.C., Correspondence 1944-1960 (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
  - Football Rules, Krieger, E.C., Publications (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Football Rules, Porter, H.V., Correspondence 1944-1952 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Football Rules, National Federation of State High School Athletic Association, Various Publications 1946, 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Football Rules, Miscellaneous Material (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
  - Football Examinations, Various (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Arizona Football Hall of Fame 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - National Football Hall of Fame, Miscellaneous Correspondence 1948-1953 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Official N.C.A.A. Football Guide 1961 (Box 17)
- Series XI: Basketball Materials, 1949-1971
  - Basketball Officiating, Miscellaneous Materials, Includes 2 published articles by Emil L. Larsen (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Basketball Officials Manuals, Various (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Basketball Rules, Various Publications (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Basketball Rules, Miscellaneous Material (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Basketball Examinations, Various (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Arizona Basketball Hall of Fame, 1965-1971 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Basketball Assignments, Non-Border Conference Officials, 1949, 1953-1961 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Official N.C.A.A. Basketball Guide, 1959 (Box 18)